[
  {
    "question": "How does a pawn move?",
    "answer": "A pawn moves forward one square, but captures diagonally."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is chess?",
    "answer": "Chess is a two-player abstract strategy board game."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the goal in chess?",
    "answer": "The object of the game is to checkmate the opponent's king."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pieces are on the board at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "Sixteen \"white\" and sixteen \"black\" pieces are placed on the board at the beginning of the game."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are rooks placed at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "Rooks are placed on the outside corners, right and left edge."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are knights placed at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "Knights are placed immediately inside of the rooks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are bishops placed at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "Bishops are placed immediately inside of the knights."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the queen at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "The queen is placed on the central square of the same color of that of the piece: white queen on the white square and black queen on the black square."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the white queen located at the start of the game?",
    "answer": "The queen is placed on the central square, on the white square"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where should the black queen be at the start of the game?",
    "answer": "The queen is placed on the central square, on the black square"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the king at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "The king takes the vacant spot next to the queen."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are pawns at the beginning of the game?",
    "answer": "Pawns are placed one square in front of all of the other pieces."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who moves first?",
    "answer": "White moves first."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the king move?",
    "answer": "The king moves exactly one square horizontally, vertically, or diagonally. A special move with the king known as castling is allowed only once per player, per game"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is castling?",
    "answer": "Castling consists of moving the king two squares towards a rook, then placing the rook on the other side of the king, adjacent to it."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I castle?",
    "answer": "The king and rook involved in castling must not have previously moved;\nThere must be no pieces between the king and the rook;\nThe king may not currently be under attack, nor may the king pass through or end up in a square that is under attack by an enemy piece (though the rook is permitted to be under attack and to pass over an attacked square);"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the rook move?",
    "answer": "A rook moves any number of vacant squares horizontally or vertically. It also is moved when castling."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the bishop move?",
    "answer": "A bishop moves any number of vacant squares diagonally. (Thus a bishop can move to only light or dark squares, not both.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the queen move?",
    "answer": "The queen moves any number of vacant squares horizontally, vertically, or diagonally."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to move the knight?",
    "answer": "A knight moves to one of the nearest squares not on the same rank, file, or diagonal (in an \"L\" pattern)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is en passant?",
    "answer": "When a pawn advances two squares on its initial move and ends the turn adjacent to an enemy pawn on the same rank, it may be captured en passant by the enemy pawn as if it had moved only one square."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is promotion?",
    "answer": "If a player advances a pawn to its eighth rank, the pawn is then promoted (converted) to a queen, rook, bishop, or knight of the same color at the choice of the player (a queen is usually chosen)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is check?",
    "answer": "A king is in check when it is under attack by at least one enemy piece."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is checkmate?",
    "answer": "If a player's king is placed in check and there is no legal move that player can make to escape check, then the king is said to be checkmated, the game ends, and that player loses."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is resigning?",
    "answer": "Resigning is when a player concedes the game to the opponent."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a stalemate?",
    "answer": "The player to move is not in check and has no legal move."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a dead position?",
    "answer": "A dead position is defined as a position where neither player can checkmate their opponent's king by any sequence of legal moves."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you reach a draw?",
    "answer": "The game ends in a draw if any of these conditions occur:\n\nThe player to move is not in check and has no legal move. This situation is called a stalemate. An example of such a position is shown in the adjacent diagram.\nThe game reaches a dead position.\nBoth players agree to a draw after one of the players makes such an offer.\nThe player having the move claims a draw by correctly declaring that one of the following conditions exists, or by correctly declaring an intention to make a move which will bring about one of these conditions:\nThe same board position has occurred three times with the same player to move and all pieces having the same rights to move, including the right to castle or capture en passant (see threefold repetition rule).\nThere has been no capture or pawn move in the last fifty moves by each player, if the last move was not a checkmate (see fifty-move rule)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the 50-move rule?",
    "answer": "The fifty-move rule in chess states that a player can claim a draw if no capture has been made and no pawn has been moved in the last fifty moves."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the threefold repetition?",
    "answer": "In chess, the threefold repetition rule states that a player may claim a draw if the same position occurs three times during the game."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is insufficient material?",
    "answer": "An endgame scenario in which all pawns have been captured, and one side has only its king remaining while the other has only its king, a king plus a knight, or a king plus a bishop."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an endgame?",
    "answer": "The third and last phase of the game, when there are few pieces left on the board. The endgame follows the middlegame."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a middlegame?",
    "answer": "The part of a chess game that follows the opening and comes before the endgame, beginning after the pieces are developed in the opening. This is usually roughly moves 20 through 40."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an opening?",
    "answer": "The beginning phase of the game, roughly the first dozen moves, but it can extend much farther. In the opening players set up their pawn structures, develop their pieces, and usually castle. The opening precedes the middlegame."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a passed pawn?",
    "answer": "A pawn that has no pawn of the opposite color on its file or on an adjacent file to challenge or threaten its potential for queening."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is time control?",
    "answer": "A time control is a mechanism in the tournament play of almost all two-player board games so that each round of the match can finish in a timely way and the tournament can proceed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is flag-fall?",
    "answer": "When a player runs out of time, this event is called flag-fall."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an illegal move?",
    "answer": "An illegal move is a move not made according to a piece's possible defined movements or made according to its possible movements but such that its own king is left or placed in check."
  }
]